<chapter style="-uslm-lc:I81" id="id239e8ed0-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/ch3"><num value="3">CHAPTER 3—</num><heading>GOVERNMENT PRINTING OFFICE</heading>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id239e8ed5-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s301"><num value="301">§ 301.</num><heading> Public Printer: appointment</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President of the United States shall nominate and, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, appoint a suitable person, who must be a practical printer and versed in the art of bookbinding, to take charge of and manage the Government Printing Office. His title shall be Public Printer.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id239e8ed6-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1239">82 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/310/s210/a/1">Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 210(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/204">86 Stat. 204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id239e8eda-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s302"><num value="302">§ 302.</num><heading> Deputy Public Printer: appointment; duties</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Public Printer shall appoint a suitable person, who must be a practical printer and versed in the art of bookbinding, to be the Deputy Public Printer. He shall perform the duties formerly required of the chief clerk, supervise the buildings occupied by the Government Printing Office, and perform any other duties required of him by the Public Printer.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id23a0ffdb-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1239">82 Stat. 1239</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a0ffde-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s303"><num value="303">§ 303.</num><heading> Public Printer and Deputy Public Printer: pay</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The annual rate of pay for the Public Printer shall be a rate which is equal to the rate for level II of the Executive Schedule under subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 5. The annual rate of pay for the Deputy Public Printer shall be a rate which is equal to the rate for level III of such Executive Schedule.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id23a0ffdf-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1239">82 Stat. 1239</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/82/s204/c/1">Pub. L. 94–82, title II, § 204(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-08-09">Aug. 9, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/421">89 Stat. 421</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/s209">Pub. L. 101–520, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2274">104 Stat. 2274</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/83/s1301/a">Pub. L. 108–83, title I, § 1301(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1033">117 Stat. 1033</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a0ffe6-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s304"><num value="304">§ 304.</num><heading> Public Printer: vacancy in office</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In case of the death, resignation, absence, or sickness of the Public Printer, the Deputy Public Printer shall perform the duties of the Public Printer until a successor is appointed or his absence or sickness ceases; but the President may direct any other officer of the Government, whose appointment is vested in the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to perform the duties of the vacant office until a successor is appointed, or the sickness or absence of the Public Printer ceases. A vacancy occasioned by death or resignation may not be filled temporarily under this section for longer than ten days, and a temporary appointment, designation, or assignment of another officer may not be made except to fill a vacancy happening during a recess of the Senate.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id23a0ffe7-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1239">82 Stat. 1239</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a0ffea-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s305"><num value="305">§ 305.</num><heading> Public Printer: employees; pay</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a0ffeb-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s305/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Public Printer may employ journeymen, apprentices, laborers, and other persons necessary for the work of the Government Printing Office at rates of wages and salaries, including compensation for night and overtime work, he considers for the interest of the Government and just to the persons employed, except as otherwise provided by this section. He may not employ more persons than the necessities of the public work require nor more than four hundred apprentices at one time. The minimum pay of journeymen printers, pressmen, and bookbinders employed in the Government Printing Office shall be at the rate of 90 cents an hour for the time actually employed. Except as provided by the preceding part of this section the rate of wages, including compensation for night and overtime work, for more than ten employees of the same occupation shall be determined by a conference between the Public Printer and a committee selected by the trades affected, and the rates and compensation so agreed upon shall become effective upon approval by the Joint Committee on Printing. When the Public Printer and the committee representing the trade fail to agree as to wages, salaries, and compensation, either party may appeal to the Joint Committee on Printing, and the decision of the Joint Committee is final. The wages, salaries, and compensation so determined are not subject to change oftener than once a year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a0ffec-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s305/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Public Printer may grant an employee paid on an annual basis compensatory time off from duty instead of overtime pay for overtime work.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id23a0ffed-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1240">82 Stat. 1240</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/167">Pub. L. 91–167</ref>, <date date="1969-12-26">Dec. 26, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/453">83 Stat. 453</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/369">Pub. L. 91–369</ref>, <date date="1970-07-31">July 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/693">84 Stat. 693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a349e3-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s306"><num value="306">§ 306.</num><heading> Public Printer: employment of skilled workmen; trial of skill</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Public Printer shall employ workmen who are thoroughly skilled in their respective branches of industry, as shown by trial of their skill under his direction.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id23a349e4-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1240">82 Stat. 1240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a349e7-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s307"><num value="307">§ 307.</num><heading> Public Printer: night work</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Public Printer shall cause the public printing in the Government Printing Office to be done at night as well as through the day, when the exigencies of the public service require it.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id23a349e8-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1240">82 Stat. 1240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a349eb-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s308"><num value="308">§ 308.</num><heading> Disbursing officer; deputy disbursing officer; certifying officers and employees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349ec-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s308/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Public Printer shall appoint from time to time a disbursing officer of the Government Printing Office (including the Office of the Superintendent of Documents) who shall be under the direction of the Public Printer. The disbursing officer shall (1) disburse moneys of the Government Printing Office only upon, and in strict accordance with, vouchers certified by the Public Printer or by an officer or employee of the Government Printing Office authorized in writing by the Public Printer to certify such vouchers, (2) make such examination of vouchers as may be necessary to ascertain whether they are in proper form, certified, and approved, and (3) be held accountable accordingly. However, the disbursing officer shall not be held accountable or responsible for any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate, the responsibility for which, under subsection (c) of this section, is imposed upon a certifying officer or employee of the Government Printing Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349ed-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s308/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349ee-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s308/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon the death, resignation, or separation from office of the disbursing officer, his accounts may be continued, and payments and collection may be made in his name, by any individual designated as a deputy disbursing officer by the Public Printer, for a period of time not to extend beyond the last day of the second month following the month in which the death, resignation, or separation occurred. Accounts and payments shall be allowed, audited, and settled, and checks signed in the name of the former disbursing officer by a deputy disbursing officer shall be honored in the same manner as if the former disbursing officer had continued in office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349ef-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s308/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A former disbursing officer of the Government Printing Office or his estate may not be subject to any legal liability or penalty for the official accounts or defaults of the deputy disbursing officer acting in the name or in the place of the former disbursing officer. Each deputy disbursing officer is responsible for accounts entrusted to him under paragraph (1) of this subsection, and the deputy disbursing officer is liable for any default occurring during his service under such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349f0-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s308/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349f1-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s308/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Public Printer may designate in writing officers and employees of the Government Printing Office to certify vouchers for payment from appropriations and funds. Such officers and employees shall (A) be responsible for the existence and correctness of the facts recited in the certificate or other voucher or its supporting papers and for the legality of the proposed payment under the appropriation or fund involved, (B) be responsible and accountable for the correctness of the computations of certified vouchers, and (C) be accountable for, and required to make restitution to, the United States for the amount of any illegal, improper, or incorrect payment resulting from any false, inaccurate, or misleading certificate made by him, as well as for any payment prohibited by law or which did not represent a legal obligation under the appropriation or fund involved. However, the Comptroller General of the United States, may, at his discretion, relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for any payment otherwise proper whenever he finds that (i) the certification was based on the official records and that such certifying officer or employee did not know, and by reasonable diligence and inquiry could not have ascertained, the actual facts, or (ii) when the obligation was incurred in good faith, the payment was not contrary to any statutory provision specifically prohibiting payments of the character involved, and the United States has received value for such payment. The Comptroller General shall relieve such certifying officer or employee of liability for an overpayment for transportation services made to any common carrier covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3726">section 3726 of title 31</ref>, whenever he finds that the overpayment occurred solely because the administrative examination made prior to payment of the transportation bill did not include a verification of transportation rates, freight classifications, or land grant deductions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349f2-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s308/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The liability of such certifying officers or employees shall be enforced in the same manner and to the same extent as provided by law with respect to the enforcement of the liability of disbursing and other accountable officers. Such certifying officers and employees shall have the right to apply for and obtain a decision by the Comptroller General on any question of law involved in a payment on any vouchers presented to them for certification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id23a349f3-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1240">82 Stat. 1240</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/310/s210/b">Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 210(b)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-06">June 6, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/204">86 Stat. 204</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/459/s1/a">Pub. L. 93–459, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-20">Oct. 20, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1384">88 Stat. 1384</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/473/s2/a/5">Pub. L. 95–473, § 2(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1466">92 Stat. 1466</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s3/m/1">Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(m)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1066">96 Stat. 1066</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a349f7-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309"><num value="309">§ 309.</num><heading> Revolving fund for operation and maintenance of Government Printing Office: capitalization; reimbursements and credits; accounting and budgeting; reports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349f8-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The revolving fund of $1,000,000 established <date date="1953-07-01">July 1, 1953</date>, is available without fiscal year limitation, for—<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">the operation and maintenance of the Government Printing Office (except for those programs of the Superintendent of Documents which are funded by specific appropriations), including rental of buildings;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">attendance at meetings;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">maintenance and operation of the emergency room;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">uniforms or uniform allowances;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">boots, coats, and gloves;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">repairs and minor alterations to buildings; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">expenses authorized in writing by the Joint Committee on Printing for inspection of Government printing activities.</p>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In addition, the Public Printer shall provide capital for the fund by capitalizing, at fair and reasonable values as jointly determined by him and the Comptroller General, the current inventories, plant, and building appurtenances, except building structures and land, equipment, and other assets of the Government Printing Office.</continuation>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349f9-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The fund shall be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id23a349fa-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> reimbursed for the cost of all services and supplies furnished, including those furnished other appropriations of the Government Printing Office, at rates which include charges for overhead and related expenses, depreciation of plant and building appurtenances, except building structures and land, and equipment, and accrued leave; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id23a349fb-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> credited with all receipts including sales of Government publications, waste, condemned, and surplus property and with payments received for losses or damage to property.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349fc-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> An adequate system of accounts for the fund shall be maintained on the accrual method, and financial reports prepared on the basis of the accounts. The Public Printer shall prepare and submit an annual business-type budget program for the operations under this fund. This budget program shall be considered and enacted as prescribed by <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s9104">section 9104 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349fd-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The Inspector General of the Government Printing Office shall audit the financial and operational activities of the Government Printing Office each year. The audits shall be conducted under the direction of the Joint Committee on Printing. For purposes of the audits, the Inspector General shall have such access to the records, files, personnel, and facilities of the Government Printing Office as the Inspector General considers appropriate. The Inspector General shall furnish reports of the audits to the Congress and the Public Printer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a349fe-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> The Public Printer shall prepare an annual financial statement meeting the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3515/b">section 3515(b) of title 31</ref>, United States Code. Each financial statement shall be audited in accordance with applicable generally accepted Government auditing standards—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id23a349ff-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> by an independent external auditor selected by the Public Printer, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id23a34a00-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> at the request of the Joint Committee on Printing, by the Inspector General of the Government Printing Office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a34a01-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s309/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Comptroller General of the United States may audit the financial statement prepared under subsection (e) at his or her discretion or at the request of the Joint Committee on Printing. An audit by the Comptroller General shall be in lieu of the audit otherwise required by that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id23a34a02-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1241">82 Stat. 1241</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/604/s707">Pub. L. 93–604, title VII, § 707</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1965">88 Stat. 1965</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s3/m/2">Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(m)(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1066">96 Stat. 1066</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/458/s310">Pub. L. 100–458, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2184">102 Stat. 2184</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/163/s309">Pub. L. 101–163, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1065">103 Stat. 1065</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/520/s207">Pub. L. 101–520, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2274">104 Stat. 2274</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/69/s207/a">Pub. L. 103–69, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-11">Aug. 11, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/707">107 Stat. 707</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/316/s123/a">Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 123(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3839">110 Stat. 3839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a5bb09-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s310"><num value="310">§ 310.</num><heading> Payments for printing, binding, blank paper, and supplies</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An executive department or independent establishment of the Government ordering printing and binding or blank paper and supplies from the Government Printing Office shall pay promptly by check to the Public Printer upon his written request, either in advance or upon completion of the work, all or part of the estimated or actual cost, as the case may be, and bills rendered by the Public Printer are not subject to audit or certification in advance of payment. Adjustments on the basis of the actual cost of delivered work paid for in advance shall be made monthly or quarterly and as may be agreed by the Public Printer and the department or establishment concerned.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id23a5bb0a-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1241">82 Stat. 1241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a5bb0d-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s311"><num value="311">§ 311.</num><heading> Purchases exempt from subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41; contract negotiation authority; small purchase threshold</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a5bb0e-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s311/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Purchases may be made from appropriations under the “Government Printing Office” without reference to subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 concerning purchases for the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a5bb0f-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s311/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In addition to the authority to negotiate otherwise provided by law, the Public Printer may negotiate purchases and contracts for supplies or services for which the Public Printer determines that it is impracticable to secure competition by advertising. The Public Printer may not award a contract under this subsection unless he justifies the use of negotiation in writing and certifies the accuracy and completeness of the justification. The justification shall set out facts and circumstances that clearly and convincingly establish that advertising would not be practicable for such contract. Such a justification is final and a copy thereof shall be maintained in the Government Printing Office for at least 6 years after the date of the determination. The Public Printer may designate one or more employees of the Government Printing Office to carry out this subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id23a5bb10-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s311/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41 shall apply with respect to purchases and contracts for the Government Printing Office as if the reference to “$25,000” in clause (1) of such section were a reference to “$100,000”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id23a5bb11-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1242">82 Stat. 1242</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/151/s305/a">Pub. L. 99–151, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1985-11-13">Nov. 13, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/808">99 Stat. 808</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/57/s210/a">Pub. L. 106–57, title II, § 210(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/425">113 Stat. 425</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s3">Pub. L. 107–217, § 3</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1301">116 Stat. 1301</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s5/m/2">Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(m)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3853">124 Stat. 3853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a5bb15-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s312"><num value="312">§ 312.</num><heading> Machinery, material, equipment, or supplies from other Government agencies</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An officer of the Government having machinery, material, equipment, or supplies for printing, binding, and blank-book work, including lithography, photolithography, and other processes of reproduction, no longer required or authorized for his service, shall submit a detailed report of them to the Public Printer. The Public Printer, with the approval of the Joint Committee on Printing, may requisition such articles as are serviceable in the Government Printing Office, and they shall be promptly delivered to that office.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id23a5bb16-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1242">82 Stat. 1242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id23a5bb19-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d" identifier="/us/usc/t44/s313"><num value="313">§ 313.</num><heading> Examining boards: paper; bindery materials; machinery</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Deputy Public Printer, the superintendent of printing, and a person designated by the Joint Committee on Printing, shall constitute a board to examine and report in writing on paper delivered under contract, or by purchase or otherwise, at the Government Printing Office.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Deputy Public Printer, the superintendent of binding, and a person designated by the Joint Committee on Printing shall constitute a board to examine and report in writing on material, except paper, for the use of the bindery.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Deputy Public Printer, the superintendent of printing, and a person designated by the Joint Committee on Printing shall constitute a board of condemnation, who, upon the call of the Public Printer, shall determine the condition of presses and other machinery and material used in the Government Printing Office, with a view to condemnation.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id23a5bb1a-a7cf-11e4-a3f1-923a34b6860d">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/620">Pub. L. 90–620</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1242">82 Stat. 1242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>

